Guide to the Miriam Slifkin Papers, 1961-1994 RL.01206
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Miriam Slifkin papers
1961-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Slifkin, Miriam
RL.01206
7.5 Linear Feet
Miriam Slifkin was a feminist leader in Chapel Hill who was active from the 1960's-2000's. Miriam Slifkin founded the Chapel Hill chapter of the National Organization for Women (NOW) and the Orange County Rape Crisis Center. This collection contains NOW operational files including correspondence, newsletters, chapter organization records, speeches, fund raising, budget files, files on related organizations, and files related to sexual discrimination and sexual discrimination lawsuits. Other materials document the founding and early history of the Orange County Rape Crisis Center and her work on the Board of the Orange County Human Relations Commission. Slifkin's work to make the Morehead Scholarships at the University of North Carolina coeducational are also documented. Also included are materials for courses on Women's Studies and other educational materials, handbooks, personal files, issues of SPOKESWOMAN, NCC-LAW newsletters, and two audiocassettes of an interview of Slifkin, 1994. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
5000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Miriam Slifkin Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007.
Biographical Note
Miriam Slifkin is a women's rights activist in Chapel Hill who founded and was president of the Chapel Hill chapter of the National Organization of Women (NOW). She also helped found the Orange County Rape Crisis Center. She received a Ph.D. in Botany from the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill in 1968 and worked in that field for some time before dedicating herself to women's rights activism.
Collection Overview
This collection contains NOW operational files including correspondence, newsletters, chapter organization records, speeches, fund raising, budget files, files on related organizations, and files related to sexual discrimination and sexual discrimination lawsuits. Other materials document the founding and early history of the Orange County Rape Crisis Center. Slifkin's work to make the Morehead Scholarships at the University of North Carolina coeducational are also documented. Also included are materials for courses on Women's Studies and other educational materials, handbooks, personal files, issues of SPOKESWOMAN, NCC-LAW newsletters, and two audiocassettes of an interview of Slifkin from 1994. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has been reboxed for preservation, but the creator's original arrangement has been retained. Materials are mostly alphabetical, with NOW and ERA materials at the beginning of the collection.
Newsletters; Audiocassettes; Women's rights -- North Carolina; Women in science -- United States -- Social conditions; Women in higher education -- North Carolina -- Chapel Hill -- Social conditions; Women -- Violence against -- North Carolina; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- North Carolina; Feminists -- North Carolina -- Chapel Hill; John Motley Morehead Foundation; National Organization for Women; Chapel Hill-Carrboro Rape Crisis Center (N.C.); Slifkin, Miriam; University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- Women students; Orange County Rape Crisis Center (N.C.); Slifkin, Miriam
- Miriam Slifkin papers, 1961-2007, 12 boxes
  - NOW Newsletters, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
  - NOW Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - NOW, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - NOW Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 1)
  - NOW and Feminist Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 1)
  - NOW Business, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - NC NOW, 1975-1981 (Box 1)
  - ERA Boycott, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - ERA Correspondence and Clippings, 1971-1975 (Box 1)
  - NC NOW Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - ERA Caravan, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - ERA Carter, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - ERA Correspondence and Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - ERA General, 1972-1982 (Box 1)
  - ERA Materials, 1973-1987 (Box 2)
  - ERA Opposition, 1973-1979 (Box 2)
  - ERA Publications, 1971-1977 (Box 2)
  - ERA Fundraising, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - ERA States, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies Course Outline, undated (Box 2)
  - AAO Job Application, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Abortion, 1974-1985 (Box 2)
  - ACLU, 1977-1985 (Box 2)
  - ACLU, 1982-1986 (Box 3)
  - Athletics in Public Schools, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Apter Case, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Athletics, 1972-1980 (Box 3)
  - AWIS, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - Battered Women, 1976-1990 (Box 3)
  - Books, Lollipop and Buddies, 1975-1990 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, General, 1973-1993 (Box 3)
  - Complaints, 1971-1975 (Box 3)
  - Contacts, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  - Comparable Worth, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Community Dinner, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Cook Campaign, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Consulting, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Credit, 1972-1976 (Box 4)
  - Walter Cronkite, 1971-2007 (Box 4)
  - Democratic Party, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Domicile, 1970s (Box 4)
  - EEOC, 1978-1982 (Box 4)
  - EEOC Suit, 1978-1982 (Box 4)
  - EEOC Suit, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - EEOC Suit, 1974-1978 (Box 4)
  - Envioronment and Women, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Education, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Elected Officials, 1971-1982 (Box 4)
  - Employment, 1972-1983 (Box 4)
  - Equal Pay Act, 1978 (Box 5)
  - England, 1972-1976 (Box 5)
  - Ethics in Public Policy, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Europe, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Executive Order 11246, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - Family Archives, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Federation for Progress, North Carolina, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Women's Case, 1977-1983 (Box 5)
  - Foreign Women, General, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - France, 1976-1980 (Box 5)
  - Gaulden, Jean, 1971-1989 (Box 5)
  - GE Boycott, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Government Employed Women, 1971-1979 (Box 5)
  - Government Guidelines, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Golden Fleece, 1980-2002 (Box 5)
  - Graduation, Ph.D., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Grant Proposal, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Grifton Flood, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Grievance Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - Women's Health Resources, 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - NC Human Relations Committee, 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - Hadassah Membership Lists, 1978-2005 (Box 6)
  - HERS, Brown University, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Hiroshima/Nagasaki Commemoration Committee, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Homosexual Relations, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
  - Anti-Helms, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
  - History, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Honors, 1974-1988 (Box 6)
  - Homemakers, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Hobby, Wilbur, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Hyde Amendment, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Insurance, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
  - Insurance, 1974-1978 (Box 6)
  - Interfaith Council for Social Service, 2000-2005 (Box 6)
  - International Women's Year, 1977 (Box 6)
  - International Women's Year, 1977 (Box 6)
  - International Women's Year, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Jewish Battered Women, 1996-1998 (Box 7)
  - Jewish Feminists, 1973-1987 (Box 7)
  - Job Hunt, 1970-1979 (Box 7)
  - Job Applications, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
  - Job Applications, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Job Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Sonia, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Labor, 1977-1981 (Box 7)
  - Language, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Laws, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1973-1981 (Box 7)
  - Little, Joann, 1972-1975 (Box 7)
  - Marriage and Divorce, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - Interacting with Males, 1973-1981 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1977-2005 (Box 7)
  - Men's Problems, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Misc., 1972-1994 (Box 7)
  - Morehead Campaign, 1973-1989 (Box 7)
  - Morehead Campaign, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Morehead Campaign, 1972-1988 (Box 7)
  - Morehead Campaign, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
  - Membership Info., 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Mycological Research, 1961-1972 (Box 8)
  - NC Coalition Against Sexual Assault, 1997 (Box 8)
  - NCCLU, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - NC NOW, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Nepotism, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - NC School of Science and Math, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Name Change, 1974 (Box 8)
  - NIEHS Complaint, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Orange County Human Resources Commission, 1989-1993 (Box 8)
  - OCHRC Correspondence, etc., 1987-1994 (Box 8)
  - OCHRC Minutes, 1988-1994 (Box 8)
  - OCHRC Pauli Murray Award, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
  - OCHRC Publicity, 1988-1993 (Box 8)
  - Proposals, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Philosophy, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Poverty & Welfare, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Parliamentary Procedures, undated (Box 8)
  - Political Caucus, undated (Box 8)
  - PEER, 1979-1982 (Box 8)
  - Project on Status of Women, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - PROSE Law Newsletters, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Psychological Problems, 1970-1974 (Box 8)
  - President's Advisory Committee on Women, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Pregnancy, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Quest, a Feminist Quarterly, 1974 (Box 8)
  - RCC Grievances, 1988-1993 (Box 8)
  - Rape, 1974-1989 (Box 8)
  - Rape Crisis Association, 1975-1978 (Box 8)
  - Rape Crisis Center, 1974-2006 (Box 8)
  - Rape Crisis Center, 1987-1994 (Box 8)
  - Rape Crisis Center Clippings, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
  - Rape, Sexual Assault Laws, 1973-1985 (Box 9)
  - Rape Crisis Center Brochures, 1992 and undated (Box 9)
  - Rape Crisis Center, undated (Box 9)
  - Rape Material, 1975-1990 (Box 9)
  - Recommendations, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Resumes, undated (Box 9)
  - Religion, 1972-1979 (Box 9)
  - Role Playing, Consciousness Raising, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Save our Democracy Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Sayings and Language, undated (Box 9)
  - Schools, 1971-1973 (Box 9)
  - Science, Women in, 1973-1989 (Box 9)
  - Scientific Work, 1950-1965 (Box 9)
  - Secretaries, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Sexism in Education, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Sexism and Education, 1973-1976 (Box 9)
  - Sex Roles, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
  - Sexist Statement Cartoons, 1974 (Box 9)
  - SHE Publication, 1973-1978 (Box 9)
  - Smoking, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Social Security Laws, 1974-1980 (Box 9)
  - Songs, 1973-1981 (Box 9)
  - State Government, 1973-1977 (Box 9)
  - Status & Education of Women, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Stewart ERA Campaign, 1977-1980 (Box 9)
  - Student Interviews, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Speeches, 1972-1978 (Box 10)
  - Statistics, 1975-1978 (Box 10)
  - State Laws, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Carl Stewart, 1980 (Box 10)
  - State and Southern Region NOW, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Support Systems, 1978-1981 (Box 10)
  - Support Systems, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Surveys & Statistics, 1973-1980 (Box 10)
  - Textbook Study, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Textbook Guidelines, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Title IX Residency, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Treasury, NOW, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - UNC Discussion, 1977 (Box 10)
  - UNC Discrimination, 1971-1977 (Box 10)
  - UWAA, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
  - University Meeting, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
  - UN, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Universities, 1970-1974 (Box 10)
  - Village Companies Foundation, 1981-1987 (Box 11)
  - Vocational Education, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Violence Against Women, 1997-2000 (Box 11)
  - Wage and Hour, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Welfare, 1973-1978 (Box 11)
  - Westminster Alley, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Who's Who, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Ella May Wiggins, 1975-2004 (Box 11)
  - Women's Center, 1974-1999 (Box 11)
  - Women's Equity Action League, 1975-1977 (Box 11)
  - Women's Health Resources Center, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
  - Women's Studies Course, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Work, 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Women's Groups, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Spokeswoman, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Spokeswoman, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - NCC-LAW, 1983-1988 (Box 12)
  - Memoirs, 2007 (Box 12)
  - NIEHS, 1971-1974 (Box 12)
  - Cassette tape of Student Interview, 1994 (Box 12)
  - "An Intelligent Woman's Guide to Dirty Words," 1973 (Box 12)
  - OCRCC Board Packet, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - New Pioneers, 1980 (Box 12)